lytro.com 2017-03-26

# Lytro - Legal

## PRIVACY POLICY

effective October 16, 2014

Lytro, Inc. (“Lytro,” “we,” or “us”) continually strives to improve the experience of using Lytro products and services and to offer compelling and innovative ways to take and experience pictures. These are the primary goals in collecting information from our customers and web and mobile visitors (“you”).

This policy describes how we collect, use, and disclose information we receive from you. We may update it from time to time. We will notify you of any material changes by posting the new policy and a redline of the changes on our website.

## Information We Collect

Information about you that can be used to contact or identify you, or that can be used to identify you when combined with other information, is “personally identifiable information.” Some of the information that we collect from you is personally identifiable information, and some isn’t.

## Lytro.com

When you purchase a Lytro product from Lytro.com, you provide us with your name, email, phone number, shipping and billing addresses, credit card information, and other information you affirmatively provide. We record the serial number of the Lytro camera that has been shipped to the purchaser. When you register as a user of Lytro.com, you provide your name, country of residence, and email address and create a password and a public username. If you elect to register via a social network platform such as Facebook, we will request your name, email, and username from such platform and will prefill them for you on Lytro.com, but you can change them on Lytro.com. We also ask for other permissions to receive information from your social network account, such as contacts and the ability to post to your social network. When you register via a social network such as Facebook, we automatically associate your Lytro.com account with your social network account to facilitate your logging in on Lytro.com. You may disassociate the accounts by changing your Lytro.com settings to remove your social network account or by removing Lytro from your list of applications on your social network.

If you are a registered user, you may mark albums you upload on Lytro.com as public. We refer to albums that you have not marked as public as “unlisted” pictures. The Lytro mobile application allows you to share your living pictures with others via Lytro.com. When you do so, your pictures will go to a “Mobile Uploads” album on Lytro.com, which is pre-set as a public album. On lytro.com, you can change the settings of the “Mobile Uploads” album to unlisted. Public albums can be viewed and shared by all Lytro.com visitors and users and are searchable on Lytro.com and by third-party search engines such as Google. In accordance with our Terms of Use, we can display and feature in public areas of Lytro.com and on social media certain of your public living pictures selected by us. Unlisted albums can be viewed and shared by the user who uploaded them and by others who know the link to the pictures. The recipients of a link from the user can further forward it or publicly post it. Anyone who knows the link is able to access the unlisted album on Lytro.com and can further “like” or share the album or pictures from it on third-party sites such as Facebook. Unlisted pictures exposed in this way may show up in search indices and become easily discoverable by people who do not have the link to them. As such, the privacy of unlisted albums and pictures is not in our control, and users should take reasonable precautions with posting and sharing their pictures.

Pictures taken with a Lytro camera may contain metadata such as, for example, camera settings and caption. When you upload pictures to Lytro.com, this data is transmitted to us and may be available to viewers of the pictures.

We may store your information, including pictures and personally identifiable information, on servers and networks located outside your country of residence.

When you delete your pictures from Lytro.com, we will remove them from your account view as soon as possible, and in any event within 48 hours unless there are unforeseen circumstances. Residual copies may remain on our servers for up to 90 days. After such period, we may retain copies only if we are required by law, regulation or legal process. Lytro cannot control the retention and deletion of copies and thumbnails of your living pictures that have been shared on other websites.

Your comments on Lytro.com display your profile information (if available) and user name or name. Comments to public pictures and in other public areas on our website are public and searchable on Lytro.com and by third-party search engines such as Google. Comments to unlisted pictures can be viewed by Lytro.com visitors with a link to the pictures. We treat deleted comments and comments to deleted pictures the same way we treat deleted pictures.

When you visit our website, certain information is automatically recorded. Generally, we use this information in an aggregated and anonymized way. If we need to combine it with personally identifiable information, we treat it as such. Automatically collected information includes:

  * Statistical or technical information such as, for example, your computer’s Internet Protocol address, operating system and browser type, time and date, and how you use, navigate through, and interact with the website. For registered users of, or purchasers on, our website, we link this data (including historical data) to the individual’s email address.
  * Information collected via “cookies,” which are small data files that we transfer to your computer for record-keeping purposes. We primarily use cookies for login session management. You can change the options on your browser to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from a website. If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to use all portions or functionality of our website. For more information, see our Cookie Policy.  

  * We use third parties to collect anonymized and aggregated demographic and website use information such as, for example, type of browser and operating system, location, referring website, Internet service provider (or, in the case of mobile devices, mobile carrier), and type of device.

If you would like to learn how to opt out from third-party services that collect information on our website, please visit our [opt-out page](https://support.lytro.com/hc/en-us/articles/200863310-3rd-party-cookies-who-s-getting-them-how-to-opt-out).

We use Adobe Flash shared object (commonly known as “Flash cookies”) to assist our visitors with seeing new features and to facilitate the use of Flash player on our website. We do not collect information back from Flash cookies. You can manage Flash cookies by using Adobe’s tool found [here](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html).

## Lytro Desktop Application

We may collect the following data through the Lytro desktop application:

  * technical and statistical data about the usage of the Lytro desktop application and on-camera software;
  * technical information about the Lytro camera such as serial number, firmware version, and product version; and
  * technical information about your computer such as hardware specifications and operating system.

## Emails and Other Communications

From time to time, we send education, marketing, product support, and research emails. Some of our emails are based on registered user information collected on our website, such as picture uploads. Our marketing emails relate to our product and services offerings: software, camera equipment, camera accessories, promotions, news, and events. Our emails may contain “beacons,” which are small images that inform us about recipients’ receptiveness to our emails. Our third-party mail service provider also provides us with anonymized and aggregated demographic information about the respondents to our emails. In our emails, we may also ask you to voluntarily provide us with additional information about you. Generally, we use information from our marketing and research communications in an aggregated and anonymized way. When our business needs require, we combine it with personally identifiable information, and in such cases we treat it as such. You can unsubscribe from our marketing and research emails by following the instructions included in them.

We may also communicate with you about your order or account, or to address your questions.

## Social Media

We have a presence on various social media platforms, such as Facebook, Twitter, and YouTube. We receive from them anonymized and aggregated demographic and use information related to our presence on the respective social media platform.

From time to time, we conduct contests and sweepstakes on our social media channels or in cooperation with other partners. If you participate in such contests and sweepstakes, we may collect information from you, as described in the terms of the respective contest or sweepstake.

## How We Use This Information

We continually strive to improve the experience of using Lytro products and services and to offer compelling and innovative ways to take and experience pictures. These are the primary goals in collecting information from our customers, users and visitors.

We use collected information to:

  * complete our transactions with you and keep a record of our dealings with you;
  * help you learn how to use our products and services;
  * offer, facilitate, personalize, and improve our products and services;
  * provide you with customer support;
  * perform quality assurance and business analyses;
  * communicate with you about our products and services;
  * better understand your Lytro experience and your needs and interests;
  * develop new products and services; and
  * comply with legal process and for enforcement purposes as described below.

We may combine information we collect through our website with information we collect from other Lytro sources and from third parties.

## Information Sharing and Disclosure

In our ordinary course of business, we do not sell or provide your information to unaffiliated third parties for their own direct marketing purposes. We may share information in the following circumstances:

## Service Providers and Partners

We may employ or partner with third parties to facilitate our services or provide them on our behalf, to perform website-related services (for example, data storage, maintenance, database management, web analytics and improvement of our website’s features), to integrate their services with ours (such as Facebook, Twitter, etc.), to assist us in communicating with you, to provide customer support, or to assist us in analyzing how our website and services are used. These third parties have access to your information solely for the purpose of performing these respective tasks.

## Affiliated Parties

We may share your information with our subsidiaries, affiliated companies, or business partners with whom we jointly offer products and services.

## Compliance with Legal Requirements; Enforcement

We also may disclose your information if we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to (1) comply with any law, regulation, legal process, administrative or other government proceeding, (2) protect against misuse or unauthorized use of our website, products, or services, (3) prevent and address fraud or technical issues; (4) enforce our rights, policies and agreements or defend ourselves in legal or government proceedings; or (5) protect our and our customers’ rights, property, and safety.

## Business Transactions

We may sell, transfer, or otherwise share some or all of our assets, including your information, in connection with a merger, acquisition, or sale of assets, or if we dissolve, reorganize our business, or cease operating as a going concern (for example, in the event of a bankruptcy).

## Security

Safeguarding your information is important to us. We employ reasonable measures designed to protect personally identifiable information from unauthorized access, destruction, use, modification, or disclosure. These measures include:

  * performing internal and external review of security measures and practices;
  * implementing industry-recognized security safeguards such as encryption of data transmitted over the Internet and use of “secure cookies”;
  * using PCI-compliant vendors for processing credit card payments;
  * anonymizing and aggregating data when business needs permit; and
  * entering into confidentiality agreements with employees and service providers.

While we are striving to protect your information, there are no impenetrable security measures. We cannot guarantee the protection of information from accident, interception, or misappropriation.

## Information from Children

We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with personally identifiable information, he or she should contact us at legal@lytro.com. If we discover that a child under 13 has provided us with personally identifiable information, we will delete such information from our files.

## Collection of Information by Third-Party Sites

Our website may contain links to or integrations with other sites such as social media websites, community feedback platforms, etc., whose information practices may be different than ours. Visitors should consult the other sites' privacy notices, as we have no control over information that is collected by these third parties.

## Contacting Us

If you have any questions or concerns about this privacy policy, please contact us at [legal@lytro.com](mailto:legal@lytro.com) or by writing to Privacy Officer, c/o Lytro, Inc., 1300 Terra Bella Avenue, Suite 100, Mountain View, CA 94043.

© Lytro, Inc. Lytro and the Lytro logo are trademarks of Lytro, Inc.

[Redline Against Privacy Policy (10/16/2014)](https://s3.amazonaws.com/lytro-corp-assets/legal/ui/downloads/redlines/Privacy-Policy-Redline-\(English_2014-10-16_v_2014-06-02\).pdf)
